<?xml version='1.0' encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" []>
<book lang="en">

    <xi:include href="bookinfo.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />

    <!-- prefácio -->
    <preface>
        <title>Demoiselle Audit</title>
        <para>
            The Demoiselle Audit was created to meet a need that the community had a way of historicizing
             the events of the applications developed with Demoiselle Framework. Since early as the concept of the component
             seek technologies, and literary references on industry standards, best practices and what information would be
             capable of registering a moment and make it an input for a possible audit.
        </para>
        <para>
           We use two main sources of reference COBIT and NIST. We suggest that these sources are used as the basis for
             the effective implementation of a consistent process so that in case of audit the same is valid. The Demoiselle Audit is
             only one piece in the set of procedures which guarantee a good audit, only the use of the component is not enough
             in cases of lawsuits, and the confiabialidade invioalabilidade must be guaranteed for such information to be
             considered relevant.
        </para>
        <para>
            O Demoiselle Audit é dividido em três módulos e uma implementação de um dashboard para auxilio no desenvolvimento.
            <orderedlist numeration="arabic">
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <caption>Core</caption>
                       Main module of the system funicona with an aggregator to support pluggability of Auditors and
                         Processors and has fault tolerance mechanism.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <caption>Auditores</caption>
                        The module responsible for observing and capturing application information and send to the Core. implementation
                         Reference Auditor will capture the persistence layer of the application running in conjunction with JPA
                         collecting the data immediately after the CRUD operation has been completed.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <caption>Processadores</caption>
                        The person responsible for completion of the procedure, module, ie it has the task to continue the track element.
                         The reference implementation of the processor sends a REST service, but there may be implementations where they are
                         sent to a NoSQL database, the same database application, or even a messaging service.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                 <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <caption>Dashboard</caption>
                       This implementation is not part of the operating mechanism Demoiselle Audit, but serves as a tool
                         support the implementation and development of the component, it consists of four types of visualizations
                         persisted the Demoiselle Audit and contains a REST service that receives the path generated by the implementation of
                         Reference Processor, supporting the implementation of the component.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
        </para>
        <para>

             <mediaobject>
                <imageobject role="html">
                    <imagedata fileref="images/SP800-92.pdf" align="center"
                                                   format="PDF" scalefit="1" width="75%" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>NIST
                    </para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>
        <para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject role="fo">
                    <imagedata fileref="images/Arquitetura.png" align="center"
                                                   format="PNG" scalefit="1" width="75%" />
                </imageobject>
                <imageobject role="html">
                    <imagedata fileref="images/Arquitetura.png" align="center"
                                                   format="PNG" scalefit="1" width="75%" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Architecture of the tool Demoisele Audit.
                    </para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>
        <para>
            Trilha
        </para>
        <para>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject role="fo">
                    <imagedata fileref="images/parsertamanhoreduzido.png"
                                                   align="center" format="PNG" scalefit="1" width="75%" />
                </imageobject>
                <imageobject role="html">
                    <imagedata fileref="images/parsertamanhoreduzido.png"
                                                   align="center" format="PNG" scalefit="1" width="75%" />
                </imageobject>
                <caption>
                    <para>Modelo de Funcionamento do Parser.
                    </para>
                </caption>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>
     </preface>


    <!-- índice -->
    <toc />

    <!-- capítulos -->

    <xi:include href="core.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
    <xi:include href="auditors.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
    <xi:include href="processors.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
    <xi:include href="configuracao.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />

    <xi:include href="colaboracao.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
    <xi:include href="releasenotes.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />

    <xi:include href="quickstart.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />

</book>
